Applied and Decorative Arts Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Applied and Decorative Arts Lantern Slide Collection
1900-1960
VRC 2200
Yale University Arts Library
30.33
91 boxes
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of American and European applied and decorative arts, including arms and armor, calligraphy, ceramics, commercial design, enamels, furniture, gems, glass, illuminated manuscripts, industrial design, intarsia, ivory, medals, metalwork, mosaics, musical instruments, numismatics, rugs, seals, stage design, tapestry, textiles, wallpaper, wood carving. Classical Greek and Roman materials in all applicable media are located in the Department of Classics, Phelps Hall 402, Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, 06520.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of American and European applied and decorative arts, including arms and armor, calligraphy, ceramics, commercial design, enamels, furniture, gems, glass, illuminated manuscripts, industrial design, intarsia, ivory, medals, metalwork, mosaics, musical instruments, numismatics, rugs, seals, stage design, tapestry, textiles, wallpaper, wood carving.
Classical Greek and Roman materials in all applicable media are located in the Department of Classics, Phelps Hall 402, Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, 06520.
Arrangement
Arranged by medium. Principal sub-divisions by country and where known, artist name. Some sections preceded by materials arranged chronologically or by technique.
Decorative arts; Slides; Lantern slides; Reproductions
- Arms and Armor (Box 1)
  - France (Box 1)
  - Germany (Box 1)
  - Italy (Box 1)
- Bookbinding (Box 1)
- Calligraphy (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Britain (Box 1–2)
  - France (Box 2)
  - Germany (Box 2)
- Ceramics (Box 2)
  - Egypt (Box 2)
  - Anatolia (Box 2)
  - Mesopotamia (Box 2)
  - Persia (Box 2)
  - Coptic (Box 2)
  - Early Christian (Box 2)
  - Byzantine (Box 3)
  - Austria (Box 3)
  - Britain (Box 3)
    - Chelsea (Box 3)
    - Lambeth (Box 3)
    - Liverpool (Box 3)
    - Staffordshire (Box 3)
    - Wedgwood (Box 3)
  - Denmark (Box 3)
  - France (Box 3)
  - Germany (Box 4)
  - Holland (Box 4)
  - Italy (Box 4)
  - Spain (Box 4)
  - Sweden (Box 4)
  - United States (Box 4)
    - Earthenware (Box 4)
    - Stoneware (Box 4)
    - Porcelain (Box 4)
- Commercial Design (Box 5)
  - Magazine Covers (Box 5)
  - Posters (American and European) (Box 5)
  - Signs (Box 5)
- Enamels (Box 5)
  - Early Medieval (Box 5)
  - Flanders (Box 5)
  - France (Box 6)
    - Pre-12th century (Box 6)
    - 12th century (Box 6)
    - 13th century (Box 6)
    - 14th century (Box 6)
    - 16th century (Box 6)
    - 17th century (Box 6)
  - Germany (Box 6)
  - Italy (Box 6)
  - Russia (Box 6)
  - Spain (Box 6)
- Furniture (Box 6)
  - General (Box 6)
  - Egypt (Box 6)
    - Tomb of Tut-ahnkamen (Box 7)
  - Austria (Box 7)
  - Belgium (Box 7)
  - Britain (Box 7)
    - 16th century (Box 7)
    - 17th century (Box 7–8)
    - Queen Anne (Box 8)
    - George II (Box 8)
    - Kent (Box 8)
    - Chippendale (Box 8)
    - Early Classic Revival (Box 8–9)
    - Late Classic Revival (Box 9)
    - Victorian (Box 9)
    - Late 19th century (Box 9–10)
      - Burges, William (Box 10)
      - Butterfield, William (Box 10)
      - Eastlake, Charles (Box 10)
      - Hunt, Holman (Box 10)
      - Mackinstosh, C.R. (Box 10)
      - MacMurdo, Arthur (Box 10)
      - Morris, William (Box 10)
      - Pugin, A. Welby (Box 10)
      - Voysey, C.F.A (Box 10)
      - Webb, Philip (Box 10)
    - 20th century (Box 10)
  - Denmark (Box 10)
  - Finland (Box 10)
  - France (Box 10)
    - 13th century (Box 10)
    - 15th century (Box 10)
      - Chests (Box 10)
      - Credences (Box 10)
    - 16th century (Box 10)
      - Louis XII (Box 10)
      - Francois I (Box 10)
    - 17th century (Box 10)
      - Henri II (Box 10)
      - Louis XIV (Box 11)
    - 18th century (Box 11)
      - Regence (Box 11)
      - Louis XV (Box 11)
        - Caskets (Box 11)
        - Chairs (Box 11)
        - Clocks (Box 12)
        - Consoles and Tables (Box 12)
        - Desks (Box 12)
        - Mirrors and Frames (Box 12)
    - 19th century (Box 12–13)
      - Empire (Box 13)
      - Romantic Revival (Box 13)
      - Art Nouveau (Box 13)
    - 20th century (Box 13)
  - Germany (Box 13)
    - 15th century (Box 13)
    - 16th century (Box 13)
    - 17th century (Box 13)
    - 18th century (Box 14)
      - Rococo (Box 14)
    - 19th century (Box 14)
      - Biedermeier (Box 14)
      - Thonet (Box 14)
    - 20th century (Box 14)
      - Mies van der Rohe (Box 14)
  - Italy (Box 14)
    - 15th century (Box 14)
      - Cassoni (Box 14)
      - Chairs (Box 14)
      - Tables (Box 14–15)
    - 16th century (Box 15)
      - Cabinets (Box 15)
      - Benches (Box 15)
      - Cassoni (Box 15)
      - Chairs (Box 15)
      - Credenzas (Box 15)
      - Stools (Box 15)
      - Tables (Box 15)
    - 17th century (Box 15)
  - Norway (Box 15)
  - Russia (Box 15)
  - Spain (Box 15–16)
    - 16th century (Box 16)
    - 17th century (Box 16)
    - 18th century (Box 16)
    - 19th-20th centuries (Box 16)
  - Sweden (Box 16)
  - United States [Slide boxes 16-24] (Box 16)
    - General (Box 16)
    - Shaker (Box 16)
    - Windsor (Box 16)
    - 17th century (Box 16)
      - Chests (Box 16)
      - Clocks (Box 17)
      - Cupboards (Box 17)
      - Tables (Box 17)
      - Artists, A-Z (Box 17)
        - Disbrowe (Box 17)
    - William and Mary (Box 17)
      - Chairs (Box 17)
      - Chests (Box 17)
      - Desks (Box 17)
    - 19th century (Box 17)
      - Highboys (Box 17)
      - Lowboys (Box 18)
      - Tables (Box 18)
      - Artists, A-Z (Box 18)
        - Bagnall (Box 18)
    - Queen Anne (Box 18)
      - Beds (Box 18)
      - Chairs (Box 18)
      - Chests (Box 18)
      - Clocks (Box 18)
      - Desks and Secretaries (Box 18)
      - Highboys (Box 18)
      - Lowboys (Box 18)
      - Mirrors (Box 19)
      - Tables (Box 19)
      - Artists, A-Z (Box 19)
        - Pimm, John (Box 19)
        - Savey, Willian (Box 19)
        - Townsend, Job (Box 19)
    - Chippendale (Box 19)
      - Chairs (Box 19)
      - Chests (Box 19)
      - Chests-on-Chests (Box 19)
      - Clocks (Box 19)
      - Desks (Box 19)
      - Highboys (Box 19)
      - Lowboys (Box 19)
      - Mirrors (Box 19)
      - Secretaries (Box 20)
      - Tables (Box 20)
      - Artists, A-Z (Box 20)
        - Affleck, Thomas (Box 20)
        - Ash, Gilbert (Box 20)
        - Burnham, Benjamin (Box 20)
        - Chapin, Aaron (Box 20)
        - Chapin, Eliphale (Box 20)
        - Cogswell, John (Box 20)
        - Elliot, John (Box 20)
        - Folwell, James (Box 20)
        - Frothingham, Benjamin (Box 20)
        - Gaddard, John (Box 20)
        - Gostelow, J. (Box 20)
        - Randolph, Benjamin (Box 20)
        - Roberts, Aaron (Box 21)
        - Saveny, Willian (Box 21)
        - Townsend, Edmund (Box 21)
        - Townsend, John (Box 21)
        - Townsend and Goddard workshop (Box 21)
    - Early Classical Revival (Box 21)
      - Chairs (Box 21)
      - Chests (Box 21)
      - Clocks (Box 21)
      - Mirrors (Box 21)
      - Secretaries (Box 21)
      - Sideboards (Box 21)
      - Sofas (Box 21)
      - Tables (Box 21)
      - Artists, A-Z (Box 21)
        - Badlam, Stephen (and Simeon Skillin) (Box 21)
        - Lemon, William and McIntyre (Box 21)
        - McIntyre, Samuel (Box 21)
        - Seymour, John (Box 21)
        - Seymour, Thomas (Box 22)
        - Tabele, James (Box 22)
    - Late Classical Revival (Box 22)
    - Empire (Box 22)
      - Allison, Michael (Box 22)
      - Connelly (Box 22)
      - Hitchcock and his style (Box 22)
      - Lannuier, Charles (Box 22)
      - Mills, George (Box 22)
      - Phyfe, Duncan (Box 22)
        - Chairs (Box 22)
        - Sofas (Box 22)
        - Tables (Box 22–23)
    - Victorian (Box 23)
      - Late 19th century (Box 23)
      - 20th century designers (Box 23)
        - Bartolucci and Waldheim (Box 23)
        - Breuer, Marcel (Box 23)
        - Craig and Hatfield (Box 23)
        - Deskey, Donals (Box 23)
        - Frankl, Paul T. (Box 23)
        - Frankl Galleries (Box 24)
        - Koch, Carl (Box 24)
        - Komai, Ray (Box 24)
        - Newmarch, Billie (Box 24)
        - Payes, Ernst (Box 24)
        - Rado, L.L. (Box 24)
        - Saarinen, Eero (Box 24)
        - Sanders (Box 24)
        - Schwegler and Co. (Box 24)
        - Sloane, W & J (Box 24)
        - Stein, Richard (Box 24)
        - Wright, Frank Lloyd (Box 24)
- Gems (Box 24)
  - Early Christian (Box 24)
- Glass (Box 24)
  - Processes (Box 24)
  - Near East (Box 24)
  - Britain (Box 24)
  - France (Box 24)
  - Italy (Box 24)
  - Sweden (Box 24)
  - Spain (Box 24)
  - United States (Box 24)
    - 17th century (Box 24)
    - 18th century (Box 24–25)
    - 19th century (Box 25)
    - 20th century (Box 25)
      - Tiffany, Louis C. (Box 25)
- Illuminations (Manuscripts) (Box 25)
  - Ambrosian Calendar (Box 25)
  - Notita Dignitatum (Box 25)
  - Vergilius Romanus (Box 25)
  - Virgilius Vaticanus (Box 26)
  - Dura-Europas (Box 26)
  - Coptic (Box 26)
  - Early Christian and Byzantine (Box 26)
    - 4th century (Box 26)
    - 5th century (Box 26)
      - Cotton Genesis (Box 26)
    - 6th century (Box 26)
      - Vienna Dioscurides (Box 26)
      - Rabbula Gospels (Box 26)
      - Bassano Gospels (Box 26)
      - Sinope Gospels (Box 26)
      - Vienna Genesis (Box 26)
    - 7th century (Box 26)
      - Ashburnham Pentateuch (Box 26)
    - 8th century (Box 26)
      - Syriac Gospels (Box 26)
    - 9th century (Box 26)
      - Gregory of Nazianus (Box 26)
    - 10th century (Box 27)
      - Joshua Roll (Box 27)
      - Paris Psalter (Box 27)
      - Petropolitanus (Box 27)
    - 11th century (Box 27)
      - Menologium of Basil II (Box 27)
      - Sermons of John Chrysostom (Box 27)
      - Theriaca of Nicander (Box 27)
    - 12th century (Box 27)
      - Barberini Psalter (Box 27)
      - Gospels of Iviran (Box 27)
      - Gregory of Nazianus (Box 27)
      - Homilies of Monk James (Box 27)
      - Vatican Gospels (Box 27)
    - 13th century (Box 28)
      - Berlin Gospels (Box 28)
    - 14th century (Box 28)
      - Paris Gospels (Box 28)
  - Celtic (Box 28)
    - Book of Durrow (Box 28)
    - Echternach Gospels (Box 28)
    - Book of Kells (Box 28)
    - Lindisfarne Gospels (Box 28)
  - Merovingian (Box 28)
    - Gellone Sacramentary (Box 28)
    - Luxuell Lectionary (Box 28)
  - Carolingian [Slides boxes 28-30] (Box 28)
    - Cambrai Gospels (Box 29)
    - Charlemagne Court School (Box 29)
    - Coronation Group (Box 29)
    - Fulda School (Box 29)
    - Ebbo Gospels (Box 29)
    - Utrecht Psalter (Box 29)
    - Bamberg Gospel (Box 29)
    - Moutier-Grandval Bible (Box 29)
    - Vivian Bible (Box 29)
    - Marmonlier Sacramentary (Box 29)
    - S. Paolo Bible (Box 29)
    - Metz Sacramentary (Box 29)
    - S. Gall School (Box 30)
  - Austria (Box 30)
    - 12th-14th centuries (Box 30)
  - Britain (Box 30)
    - Benedictional of S. Aethelwold (Box 30)
    - 11th century (Box 30)
      - Cotton MS (Box 30)
      - Harley MS (Box 30)
    - 12th century (including works or collections in Cambridge, Edinburgh, London and New York) (Box 30–31)
      - Eadwine Psalter (Box 31)
      - York Psalter (Box 31)
      - Lambeth Bible (Box 31)
      - S. Edmund MS (Box 31)
      - Winchester Bible (Box 31)
    - 13th century (including works or collections in Cambridge, Dublin, London, Munich, New York, Oxford, and Paris) (Box 31–32)
      - Chronica Majore (Box 32)
      - Harley Bestiary (Box 32)
      - Robert of Linsey Psalter (Box 32)
      - William de Brailes MS (Box 32)
      - Lambeth Apocalypse (Box 32)
    - 14th century (Box 32)
      - London (Box 32)
        - S. Omer Psalter (Box 32)
        - Queen Mary's Psalter (Box 33)
  - Flanders (Box 33)
    - 11th-14th centuries (Box 33)
    - 15th century (including works or collections in Baltimore, Breslau, Brussels, Cambridge, Chantilly, London, New Haven, New York) (Box 34)
      - Grimani Breviary (Box 34)
      - Turin-Milano Hours (Box 34)
      - L'Arbe des Bailles (Box 34)
      - Historiaux de la Bible (Box 34)
  - France (Box 34)
    - 9th-10th centuries (Box 34)
    - 11th century (including works or collections in London and Paris) (Box 34)
      - Bible of St. Vaast (Box 34)
      - Apocalypse of S. Sever (Box 35)
    - 12th century (including works or collections in Dijon and Paris) (Box 35)
      - Hortus Deliciarum (Box 35)
      - Sacramentary of St. Etienne (Box 35)
    - 13th century (including works or collections in Chantilly, London, New York, Oxford, Paris, and Vienna) (Box 36)
      - Morgan Bible Moralisee (Box 36)
      - Morgan MS 638 (Box 36)
      - Morgan MS 730 (Box 36)
      - Oxford Bible Moralisee (Box 36)
      - Paris Bible Moralisee (Box 36)
      - Arroyo Apocalypse (Box 36)
      - S. Chapelle Evangeliary (Box 36)
      - St. Louis Psalters (Box 36)
    - 14th century (including works or collections in New Haven, New York, Paris, and Vienna) (Box 37)
      - Bellville Breviary (Box 37)
      - Bible of Jean de Sy (Box 37)
      - Grandes Heures du Duc de Berry (Box 37)
      - Legend of S. Denis (Box 37)
      - Petite Heures du Duc de Berry (Box 37)
      - Tres Belles Heures du Duc de Berry (Box 37)
    - 15th century (including works or collections in Aix-en-Provence, Arras, Baltimore, Brussels, Cleveland, Dresden, Lyons, Macau, New Haven, New York, Vienna, and Weingarten) (Box 38–40)
      - Passion of Eustach Marcade (Box 38–40)
      - Breviary of Philippe Lebon (Box 38–40)
      - Mortififment of Rene d'Anjou (Box 38–40)
      - Hours of Etienne Chevalier (Box 38–40)
      - Tres Riches Heures du Duc de Berry (Box 38–40)
      - Antiques Judaiques (Box 38–40)
      - Bible Moralisee (BN Ms Fr. 166) (Box 38–40)
      - BN Ms. Fr. 9199 (Box 38–40)
      - BN Ms. Lat. 6067 (Box 38–40)
      - Livre du Coeur (Rene d'Anjou) (Box 38–40)
    - 16th century (Box 41)
      - Paris (Box 41)
        - Hours of Anne of Brittany (Box 41)
  - Germany (Box 41)
    - 9th-10 centuries (Box 41)
      - Codex Egberti (Box 41)
      - Gero Codex (Box 41)
      - Gospels of Otto III (Box 41)
      - Trier fragment (Box 41)
      - Lorsch Sacramentary (Box 41)
      - S. Chapelle Gospels (Box 41)
      - Otto as Emperor (Chantilly 15654) (Box 41)
    - 11th century (Box 42)
      - Echternach Gospels (Box 42)
      - Gospels of Henry III (Box 42)
      - Gospels of Hilda of Darmstadt (Box 42)
      - Gospels of Otto III (Box 42)
      - Life of S. Lindiger (Box 42)
      - Augsburg Pericope (Box 42)
      - Sacramentary of Henry II (Box 42)
      - S. Gall Codex (Box 42)
      - Uta Codex (Box 42)
    - 12th century (Box 42)
    - 13th century (including works or collections in Heidelberg, Munich, New York City, Stuttgart, Wiesbaden, Wolfenbuttel) (Box 42–43)
    - 14th century (Box 43)
    - 15th century (Box 43)
      - Biblia Pauperum (Box 43–44)
    - 16th century (Box 44)
  - Holland (Box 44)
  - Italy (Box 44)
    - 11th-13th centuries (Box 44)
    - 14th century (including works or collections in New Haven, Rome, and Siena) (Box 44)
    - 15th century (including works or collections in London, New York, Paris, Siena) (Box 45)
      - Divine Comedy (Box 45)
      - Perugia Missal (Box 45)
      - Piccolomini Antiphonal (Box 45–46)
    - 16th century (Box 46)
  - Russia (Box 46)
  - Spain (Box 46)
- Industrial Design (Box 46)
  - Appliances (Box 46)
  - Bathroom fixtures (Box 46)
  - Elevators (Box 47)
  - Lighting fixtures (Box 47)
    - Bauhaus (Box 47)
    - Tiffany (Box 47)
  - Machines (Box 47)
  - Microscopes (Box 47)
  - Radios (Box 47)
  - Refrigerators (Box 47)
  - Sewing machines (Box 47)
  - Stoves (Box 47)
  - Tools (Box 47)
- Intarsia (Box 48)
  - Italy (Box 48)
    - Domenico di Riccolo (Box 48)
    - Fra Domenico da Bergamo (Box 48)
    - Fra Giovanni di Verona (Box 48)
    - Francesco di Giorgio (Box 48)
    - Mariano, Giuliano (Box 48)
- Ivory (Box 48)
  - Primitive (Box 48)
  - Near East (Box 48)
  - Coptic (Box 48)
  - 4th century (Box 48)
    - Ivory casket, Brescia (Box 48)
    - Nicomachi and Symmachi (Box 48)
  - 4th-5th centuries (Box 48)
    - Carrand Diptych (Florence) (Box 49)
  - 5th century (Box 49)
    - Berlin Pyxis (Box 49)
    - Book cover, Milan (Box 49)
    - Casket panels (British Museum) (Box 49)
    - Consul Basilius Diptych (Box 49)
    - Consul Felix Diptych (Box 49)
    - Consul Probas Diptych (Box 49)
    - Lampadiorum Diptych (Box 49)
    - Pola Casket (Box 49)
    - Rome/Constantinople Diptych (Box 49)
    - Stilicho and Serena Diptych (Box 49)
    - Women at the Sepulchre and Ascension (Box 49)
    - Women at the Tomb (Milan) (Box 49)
  - 6th century (Box 49)
    - Anastasius Diptych (Paris) (Box 49)
    - Diptych Leaf of Flavius Anastasius (Victoria and Albert) (Box 49)
    - Maximianus Diptych (Berlin) (Box 49)
    - Seated Empress (Vienna) (Box 49)
    - Throne of Maximianus (Box 49)
  - 9th century (Box 50)
  - 10th century (Box 50)
    - Rambona Diptych (Vatican) (Box 50)
  - 10th-11th centuries (Box 50)
    - Forty Martyrs (Berlin) (Box 50)
    - Ivory Plaque (Berlin) (Box 50)
    - Casket (Troyes) (Box 50)
  - 11th century (Box 50)
    - Harbaville Triptych (Box 50)
  - 11th-12th centuries (Box 50)
  - 13th century (Box 50)
  - Anglo-Saxon (Box 50)
    - Franks Casket (Box 50)
  - Scandanavian (Box 50)
  - Carolingian (Box 50)
    - Ada (Box 50)
    - Lorsch Gospels Cover (Box 50)
    - Lithuard (Box 50)
    - Metz (Box 51)
    - S. Gall (Box 51)
  - Britain (Box 51)
    - 10th century (Box 51)
    - 11th century (Box 51)
    - 12th century (Box 51)
    - 14th century (Box 51)
  - Flanders (Box 51)
  - France (Box 51)
    - 11th century (Box 51)
    - 14th century (Box 51)
    - 15th century (Box 52)
  - Germany (Box 52)
    - 10th century (Box 52)
      - Echternach (Box 52)
      - Milan or Reichenau (Box 52)
    - 11th century (Box 52)
    - 12th century (Box 52)
    - 13th century (Box 52)
    - 17th century (Box 52)
    - 18th century (Box 52)
  - Italy (Box 52)
  - Spain (Box 52)
- Jewelry (Box 52)
  - Egypt (Box 52)
  - France (Box 52)
- Medals (Box 53)
  - Early Medieval (Box 53)
  - France (Box 53)
    - Dupre, Guillame (Box 53)
  - Germany (Box 53)
    - Hagenauer, Friedrich, ac. 1527-1546 (Box 53)
    - Weidtz, Christoph (Box 53)
  - Italy (Box 53)
    - School of Ferrara (Box 53)
    - Antonio Veneziano (Box 53)
    - Bertoldo di Giovanni, ac. 1420-1439 (Box 53)
    - Bombarda (Box 53)
    - Caradosso (Box 53)
    - Donatello, c. 1386-1466 (Box 53)
    - Enzola Gianfrecesco (Box 53)
    - Guazzalotti, Andrea (Box 53)
    - Laurana, Francesco del (Box 53)
    - Leoni, Leone, 1509-1592 (Box 53)
    - Niccolo Fiorentino (Box 53)
    - Pasti, Matteo de, ca. 1446-1467 (Box 53)
    - Melioli, Bartolomeo, 1448-1514 (Box 53)
    - Pastorino da Siena (Box 53)
    - Pietro de Martino da Milano (Box 53)
    - Pisanello, Antonio Vittore, 1395-1455 (Box 53–54)
      - Medal, Lodovico III Gonzaga (Box 54)
      - Medal, Sigismondo Malatesa (Box 54)
    - Sangallo, Francesco da (Box 54)
    - Sperandio, Savelli (Box 54)
    - Tanaglia (Box 54)
    - Trezzo, Jacopo da (Box 54)
      - Medal of Isabella Gonzaga (Box 54)
    - Lead (Box 54)
      - Pisanello, Vittore (Box 54)
    - Bronze, Old Cast (Box 54)
    - Bronze, Later Cast (Box 54)
  - United States (Box 54)
- M etalwork (Box 55)
  - Egypt (Box 55)
  - Near East (Box 55)
    - Anatolia (Box 55)
    - Mesopotamia (Box 55)
    - Persia (Box 55)
    - Phoenicia (Box 55)
  - Dura-Europas (Box 55)
  - Early Medieval (Box 55)
    - 3rd century (Box 55)
    - 4th century (Box 55)
      - Missorium of Theodosius (Box 55)
    - 5th century (Box 55)
    - 6th century (Box 55)
    - 7th-9th centuries (Box 56)
    - 10th century (Box 56)
      - Cover of the Gospels of Gauzelin (Box 56)
    - 11th century (Box 56)
    - 12th-14th centuries (Box 56)
  - Barbarian (Box 56)
    - Nagysxentmiklos (Box 56)
    - Petrossa Treasure (Box 56)
  - Anglo-Saxon (Box 56)
  - Celtic (Box 57)
    - Ardagh Chalice (Box 57)
    - St. Patrick's Bell Shrine (Box 57)
    - Tara Brooch (Box 57)
  - Lombard (Box 57)
  - Scandinavian (Box 57)
  - Scythian (Box 57)
  - Merovingan (Box 57)
  - Carolingian (Box 57)
    - Book covers (Box 57)
    - Ciborium of King Arnulf (Box 57)
    - Reliquaries (Box 57)
      - Pepin I (Box 57)
      - Purse of St. Stephen (Box 57)
    - Tassilo Chalice (Box 57)
  - Austria (Box 58)
    - Oswald Haerdth (Box 58)
    - Josef Hoffmann (Box 58)
  - Belgium (Box 58)
  - Britain (Box 58)
    - 11th century (Box 58)
    - 12th century (Box 58)
    - 14th century (Box 58)
    - 15th-16th centuries (Box 58)
    - 17th century (Box 58)
    - 18th century (Box 58)
    - 19th-20th centuries (Box 58)
    - Known artists, A-Z (Box 58–59)
      - Adam, Robert (Box 59)
      - Burges, William (Box 59)
      - Chadwick, James (Box 59)
      - Lamere, Paul de (Box 59)
      - Storr, Paul (Box 59)
      - Watts, Benjamin (Box 59)
  - Denmark (Box 59)
    - Henning, Haukler (Box 59)
    - Jensen, George (Box 59)
  - Flanders (Box 59)
    - 11th century (Box 59)
    - 12th century (Box 59)
      - Godefroid de Huy (Box 59)
      - Nicholas of Verdun (Box 59)
    - 13th century (Box 60)
  - France (Box 60)
    - Romanesque (Box 60)
    - 10th century (Box 60)
      - S. Foy of Conques (Box 60)
    - 11th century (Box 60)
    - 12th century (Box 60)
      - Treasury of St. Denis (Box 60)
    - 13th century (Box 60)
    - 14th century (Box 61)
    - 15th century (Box 61)
    - Renaissance-18th century (Box 61)
      - Louis XIV (Box 61)
      - Louis XV (Box 61)
      - Louis XVI (Box 61)
    - 19th-20th centuries (Box 61)
      - Empire (Box 61)
      - Art Nouveau (Box 61)
      - Known artists, A-Z (Box 61)
        - Balzac, Edme (Box 61)
        - Brandt, Elgar (Box 61)
        - Caffien, Jaques (Box 61)
        - Germain, Francois Thomas (Box 61)
      - Landes, L. (Box 61)
      - Puiforcat, Jean (Box 61)
      - Roettiers, Jacques (Box 61)
      - Samson, Louis (Box 61)
  - Germany (Box 62)
    - 10th century (Box 62)
      - Cross of Lothair (Box 62)
      - Crown of the Holy Empire (Box 62)
      - Foot Reliquary of St. Andrew (Box 62)
    - 11th century (Box 62)
      - Cleveland (Box 62)
      - Essen (Box 62)
      - Hildesheim (Box 62)
      - Hildesheim (Box 62)
    - 12th century (Box 62)
      - Cleveland (Box 62)
      - Cologne (Box 62)
      - London (Box 62)
      - Vienna (Box 62)
    - 13th century (Box 63)
      - Acquamaniles (Box 63)
      - Chalice of St. Trudpert (Box 63)
      - Paten of St. Trudpert (Box 63)
      - Reliquary of Charlemagne (Box 63)
      - S. Elizabeth Shrine (Box 63)
    - 14th century (Box 63)
    - 15th century (Box 63)
    - 16th century (Box 63)
    - 19th-20th centuries (Box 63)
      - Known artists, A-Z (Box 63)
        - Brandt, M. (Box 63)
        - Henning, Naukler (Box 63)
        - Nechansky, Arnold (Box 63)
        - Raemish, W. (Box 63)
        - Wagenfeld, Wilhelm (Box 63)
        - Wilim, H.J. (Box 63)
  - Holland (Box 64)
  - Italy (Box 64)
    - Romanesque (Box 64)
    - Gothic (Box 64)
    - Renaissance-18th century (Box 64)
  - Russia (Box 64)
  - Spain (Box 64–65)
    - 11th century (Box 65)
    - 14th century (Box 65)
  - Sweden (Box 65)
    - Ahlberg, Hakon (Box 65)
    - Angman, javob (Box 65)
    - Bergh, Elis (Box 65)
    - Fougstedt, Wolter (Box 65)
    - Gibson, Sidney (Box 65)
    - Grate (Box 65)
    - Lundgren, Helge (Box 65)
    - Ollers, Edwin (Box 65)
    - Petrus, Anna (Box 65)
  - Switzerland (Box 65)
  - United States [Slide boxes 65-73] (Box 65)
    - 18th century (Box 65)
    - 19th century (Box 65)
    - Goldwork (Box 65)
      - Burt, John (Box 65)